Gladwin Louise G. Cedeño

glad.cedeno@gmail.com www.gladcedeno.com +1 (818) 984 4239

OBJECTIVE - Seasoned project manager with over ten years of experience in software and web development, hoping to advance my skills and learn the best practices of project management.

RELEVANT WORK EXPERIENCE

American Express - Project Manager / Scrum Master / Engineer (Hong Kong) - May 2016 - Feb 2021

- Supervised team and help resolve roadblocks by driving daily stand-ups across 5 different time zones (Hong Kong, India, London, New York, Phoenix)
- Supplied leadership and Product Owners current projects' status and provided acceptable expectations by presenting data, metrics and project plans.
- Ensured global business partners' satisfaction across different regions by liaising scope of work, deliverables, SLAs and giving them acceptable and justifiable timelines for every project.
- Monitored system application vulnerabilities that improved reports by 5% every month.
- Developed Excel and Macros to standardize and pull out Weekly, Bi-Weekly, Monthly and Quarterly project reports resulting in efficient and faster data collection.
- Improved team's performance by orchestrating retrospectives to the team every end of sprint.
- Supervised the estimation, budgeting and forecasting in project costs and team's portfolio in Clarity CA resulting in increased team's earnings by 6%.
- Mentored and launched on-boarding and training documents for newly hired engineers.
- Improved leadership skills just after a year in the company and was promoted to lead the whole engineering offshore team in India and US.
- Received multiple client rewards for delivering beyond expectations and building great relationships and customer satisfaction from global business partners.
- Designed and managed training for fellow engineers to learn and get ready to use the latest technologies within a couple of weeks.

Freelance Web Developer (Philippines) - Aug 2014 - May 2016

 Delivered engaging and visually compelling web designs with user-friendly UI that are cross-browser compatible and mobile responsive for at least 15 Websites for Multiple clients across US, Philippines and Australia using Wordpress and Drupal Content Management System

<u>Netsuite</u> - Web Support Engineer - (*Philippines*) Dec 2014 – May 2015

NorthgateArinso - Front-End Web Developer - (Philippines) - Mar 2011 - Aug 2014

- Formulated and implemented improvements on on site performance by implementing modern technologies specially on critical client's websites.
- Mentored and trained junior Front-End Engineers.

<u>MozCom</u> - Front-End Web Developer - (*Philippines*) - Aug 2009 – Feb 2011.

 Successfully executed and implemented latest technologie for over 30 web projects for big brands in the Philippines which increased mobile traffic and improved client's online sales.

Hewlett-Packard - SAP Support Engineer - (Philippines) May 2009 - Aug 2009

<u>Digital Information Technology</u> - Software Engineer - (Japan) Apr 2008 - Dec 2008

- Developed an intranet based site that was used internally as the technology team's professional social networking site.
- Served as the lead and managed the front-end developer team.

Oracle - Bootcamp Trainee - (Philippines) Jul 2007 - Sep 2007

MANAGEMENT SKILLS

Agile Project Management, Scrum, Rally, Clarity, Communication, Coordination, Analytical and Problem-solving, Risk Management, Organizational Management, Planning, Forecasting, Monitoring, Budgeting, Portfolio Management, Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC), DevOps, Leadership

TECHNICAL EXPERTISE - HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, C/C++, JSP, PHP, javascript, JSON, AJAX, XML, React JS, React Native, jQuery, Git, JIRA, Adobe Enterprise Management (AEM), Wordpress

OTHER TECHNICAL SKILLS - JSP, PHP, Java JSON, AJAX, XML, Prototype JS, Tortoise SVN, Sharepoint, Confluence, ServiceNow, Machine Learning, Cookie Privacy, Drupal, Shopify, SAP, COBOL, Salesforce, Netsuite, Google Workspace, Microsoft Office, Windows OS, Windows OS, Linux OS, Stripe, Adobe Photoshop

PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATIONS

- Google Project Management Course Certification
- 1 of 2 Hackathon local campus winner out of 8 teams
- Sun Certified Java Programmer 1.4 (Aug 2008)
- Japanese Language Proficiency Test (JLPT) Level 3 (Dec 2008)

EDUCATION

- California Trinity School of Business Masters in Business Administration Jul 2022 Present
- MAPUA INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY B.S. Computer Engineering Jul 2002 May 2007

BUSINESS RELATED EXPERIENCE

- Online Business Owner Sep 2020 Present
- CTO, Food Business StartUp GoGoBaon (May 2018 July 2019)
- CTO, Travel Business StartUp Wander Deals (May 2016 July 2017)

<u>LANGUAGES</u> - Tagalog (Native Speaker), English (Fluent), Japanese (Intermediate)

<u>HOBBIES AND INTERESTS</u> - Travel, Language and Culture, Photography, Events Planning, Outdoor Activities, Cooking, Calligraphy, Stock Trading, Investments, Business Start Up.